Arthur J. Pulos Papers
Arthur J. Pulos Papers
- 2000 accession
  - Articles, lectures and seminars
    - MS Review for U. of Toronto Press March 1994 (Box 39)
    - Israel Papers Lost (Box 39)
    - Israel Lectures 1994 (Box 39)
    - The Fourth Dimension 3/20 (Box 39)
    - Dimensions of Design (Box 39)
    - Japan Seminar Feb. 1981 (Box 39)
    - Papers/China/ 1995 (Box 39)
    - Type Forms (Box 39)
    - Design History (Box 39)
    - Design/Theory Evaluations (Box 39)
    - Design/Form (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 40)
    - History (Box 40)
    - Internationals 1980 (Box 40)
    - Theory (Box 40)
    - Design model photos (Box 40)
    - Reference (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous Articles (7) (Box 41)
    - Public/Consumer (Box 41)
    - Painting (Box 42)
    - Syracuse Chamber of Commerce (Box 42)
    - Syracuse Parks and Rec. (Box 42)
    - Articles (Box 42)
    - Planning Syracuse 1958 (Box 43)
    - Feasibility Study – Erie Canal Park (Box 43)
    - People/Pulos (Box 43)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 43)
    - 1960 Reference (Box 43)
    - Periodicals 2, Interiors (Box 43)
  - Magazines
    - Japanese magazines
      - Process 1987 (Box 44)
      - Axis (Box 44)
      - Design and Packaging (Box 44)
      - Design Scene (Box 44)
      - Modernism (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous magazines
      - Nand (Box 45)
      - Design 1960-1968 (Box 45)
      - Esthetique Industrielle (Box 45)
      - Form (Box 45)
      - Premio Small Industrial Design (Box 45)
      - Design Magazine Sp. 1960 -Nov. 1968 (Box 46)
      - Industrial Design May 1980 - Sept. 1981 (Box 46)
      - Design Aug. 1961 – Sept. 1974 (Box 47)
      - Design Feb. 1967 – Nov. 1971 (Box 48)
      - Design Scene (Box 48)
      - Design Quarterly Reports (Box 48)
      - Miscellaneous Russian and German Magazines (Box 49)
      - Craft Magazine 1950-1966 (Box 50)
      - Files and Articles for Craft Magazine (Box 50)
  - Slides and photographs
    - Slides
      - Modern Design in Japan (Box 51)
      - 1965-1970 (Box 51)
      - 1950's Lecture Fall 1985 (Box 51)
      - 1930 (Box 51)
      - Products 1 (Box 51)
      - 1960's (Box 52)
      - ADA Illustrations 231-261 Chapter 8 Section 1 (Box 52)
    - Photographs
      - Folder 3 (black and white product photographs) (Box 52)
      - Products 2 (Box 52)
      - Black Binder (black and white photographs) (Box 52)
      - NEA – IDSA Grant 1976 (Box 52)
    - Travel Slides and Photographs
      - Osaka (Box 52)
      - Atlantic City China and Glass Show 1963 (Box 52)
      - Taiwan Lecture (Box 52)
      - Hiroshima 1989 (Box 52)
      - Costa Rica Oct. 1984 (Box 52)
      - Boston Graveyards (Box 52)
      - Paris (Box 52)
      - Budapest (Box 52)
      - Canastota (Box 52)
      - Munich and Athens 1968 (Box 52)
      - Syracuse (Box 52)
      - Everson Museum (Box 52)
      - Bulgaria (Box 52)
      - Lake Placid (Box 52)
      - Armco St. Louis 1975 (Box 52)
      - Milan 1983 (Box 52)
      - Mexico 1972 (Box 52)
      - Hawaii 1973 (Box 52)
      - Istanbul (Box 52)
      - Moscow (Box 52)
      - England (Box 52)
      - Rumania 1969 (Box 52)
      - Leningrad Exhibit (Box 52)
      - Mexico – 1978 (Box 52)
      - Athens (Box 52)
      - Poland (Box 52)
      - Leningrad (Box 52)
  - Material shifted due to water damage of boxes
    - ADA Extra (Box 54)
    - Bel Geddes (Box 54)
    - Bits and pieces of lectures (Box 54)
    - Background (Box 54)
    - Reference material (Box 54)
    - Mechanical Bankers of America (Box 54)
    - Novel - Revolution (Box 54)
    - Binders of Slides
      - ADA & ADE (Box 55)
      - ADE Master Set of Slides (Box 55)
      - American Design Adventure (Box 55)
      - American Design Ethic (Box 55)
      - Architecture (Box 55)
      - Art (Box 55)
    - Binders
      - Renwick (Box 56)
      - Interiors (Box 56)
      - ADA Illustrations (Box 56)
      - Unlabelled — slides dated September 1987 (Box 56)
      - Acknowledgements (Box 56)
      - Bibliography (Box 56)
      - Index American Design Experience (Box 56)
    - Paper Files
      - Illustration discards (Box 56)
      - Chapter 5 1960's discards (Box 56)
      - 1970 illustration discards (Box 56)
      - 1978 illustration discards (Box 56)
      - Chapter 8 Products discards (Box 56)
      - Furniture illustrations Chapter 2 (Box 56)
      - Graphics packaging Ch 7 (Box 56)
      - Folder, unlabelled (Box 56)
      - John Vassos 1898-1985 (Box 56)
      - Designers Theory and Philosophy (Box 56)
    - Envelope
      - Corporate Color (Box 56)
    - Green duotang
      - Photography (Box 56)
    - Binders
      - ADE Chapter 2 (Box 57)
      - ADE Chapter 3 (Box 57)
      - ADA Chapter 3 (Box 57)
      - ADE Chapter 5 (Box 57)
      - ADA Chapter 4 (Box 57)
      - AJP/PDA (DM-RO) (Box 57)
      - ADA Chapter 2 Illustrations (Box 58)
      - ADA Chapter 2 Illustrations (Box 58)
      - ADA Chapter 3 Illustrations (Box 58)
      - Binder unlabelled slides (Box 58)
      - Slide binder, empty; prints from National Gallery of Art in back cover pocket; Index of American Design Experience and 1 Letter and print from Corning Glass in front cover pocket (Box 58)
      - ADE 3-4 Illustrations (Box 58)
    - Videos
      - Carnegie-Mellon Integrated Design/Marketing Program Universal Design Initiative (Box 59)
    - Binders
      - Piper Interior/ Exterior Selector (Box 59)
      - SBS — Company Identity Manual (Box 59)
      - Rockwell International — Corporate Identity Guidelines (Box 59)
      - The Eighth Annual Design Management Conference (Box 59)
      - Piper — Corporate Identity Manual (Box 59)
      - Brown paper cover (cover not labelled): Notes: Venturing Hearing in Las Vegas (Box 59)
      - Industrial Design Magazine — Index Pages (Box 59)
      - Black paper cover (cover not labelled): Design Management and News (Box 59)
      - Blue paper cover (cover not labelled): Australia Design Printout (Box 59)
      - Light blue cover (cover not labelled): Archives of American Art Smithsonian Institution — A Checklist of the Collection (Box 59)
    - Small Notebook — China External Trade Development Council (Box 59)
    - Brochure — Manichi Industrial Design Promotional Campaign (Box 59)
    - Brochure — Metropolitan Development Association of Syracuse (Box 59)
    - Box of Photographs — Miscellaneous — Conferences? (Box 59)
    - Envelope — IDSA — Photographs and Slides of Power Tools (Box 59)
    - Folder not labeled — Industrial Design Awards? (Box 59)
    - Brochure — Salone Internationale par L' Officio (Box 59)
    - Envelope — Keenan Special Collections — Bird Rm. 600 "Print from Pulos Collection — Rush) (Box 59)
    - Binders
      - Furniture (Box 60)
      - Transportation (Box 60)
      - ADA Chapter 9 (Box 60)
      - ADA Chapter 9 II (Box 60)
      - ADA Chapter 2 (Box 60)
      - ADA 7/3 (Box 60)
    - Envelopes
      - Identification for Alitalia Airlines — Landor Associates (Box 61)
      - Corporate Design Program Automobile Club of America (Box 61)
      - Interior of Commuter Car — BART — California - 1972 (Box 61)
      - Cannondale Bicycle Trailer — CA — 1972 (Box 61)
      - Chromatics China, Glassware and Stainless Steel Flatware (Box 61)
      - Gerald Gulotta FDR Block China Co. (Box 61)
      - Crown SC Fork Lift Truck (Box 61)
      - Richardson, Smith CA 1972 (Box 61)
      - Foregger 710 Anesthesia Control Center Manolog CA. 1976 (Box 61)
      - Product Line of Hospital Beds — Inter Royal Corp. 1971 (Box 61)
      - Air Bladder Ski Boot — Robert S. Gersin CA (Box 61)
      - Series 60 Level 66 Computer S15H Control Center Honeywell Information System Inc. CA 1978 (Box 61)
      - Boeing Company's 727 Jet (Box 61)
      - La Potagerie. George Melon and Co. CA. 1971 (Box 61)
      - Lunar 1 Combination AM/FM Radio-Clock Yamasaki Srecht Inc. CA. 1987 (Box 61)
      - Logotype for Merrill Lynch Corporation. (Box 61)
      - Nimrod Tent Camper Series III. Richardson and Smith 1972 (Box 61)
      - Sno-Dro Plane. Dave Ellies Industrial C.C. 1974 (Box 61)
      - Steelcase Series 9000 Modular System. Steelcase Inc. CA. 1973 (Box 61)
      - Symbol of Access Designers Inc. Cohabitation International. 1968 (Box 61)
      - Transit Information Directory — Samuel Lebowitz (Box 61)
      - Triangle Chair. STDW 1975 (Box 61)
      - Outdoor Living Furniture-Des: Richard Schultz CA. 1966 (Box 61)
      - Symbol for Recycling. (Box 61)
      - Creative Playthings (Box 61)
    - Files
      - ADE Vol. II Printouts of Photos (Box 61)
      - 11/83 Master Request Forms (Box 61)
      - 11/9/82 American Design Experience (Box 61)
      - I-Z Requests for Information (Box 61)
      - Library of Congress (Box 61)
      - Photograph Correspondence (Box 61)
      - Illustrations (Box 61)
      - Illustration Discards (Box 61)
      - Photos on Order at SU (Box 61)
      - Information Requests and Specific Photographs (Box 61)
      - Photos to look Up (Possibly) Later (Box 61)
      - 1940-1959 (Box 61)
      - Letters to Type and Go Out (Box 61)
      - Chapter 8 Sectional Illustration Possibilities (Box 61)
      - Chapter 8 Products Discard/Background Info. (Box 61)
      - Photos Requested (Box 61)
      - Photos Waiting for Letters to be written Correspondence (Box 61)
      - Photos Now at Photographer (Box 61)
      - Check Off Lists of Photos (Box 61)
      - ADE Vol. II (Box 61)
    - Slides and Photos
      - Design (Box 62)
      - Graphics (Box 62)
      - Mounts (Box 62)
      - Exhibits (Box 62)
      - Lescaze 1 (Box 62)
      - Lescaze 2 (Box 62)
      - PDA (Box 62)
      - Loewy (Box 62)
      - Loewy, R. (Box 62)
      - R. Wright (Box 62)
      - Graphics (Box 62)
      - History 19th (Box 62)
      - Pulos 4 Graphics (Box 62)
      - Pulos 2 Exhibits (Box 62)
      - Piper (Box 62)
      - Small Paper Box Unlabelled Misc. (Box 62)
      - Glass Plates Furniture (Box 62)
      - Greg Control Panel (Box 62)
      - Small Paper Box (Box 62)
      - Jewelry (Box 62)
      - Plastic Panels (Box 62)
      - Pulos Silver (Box 62)
      - Colonial Silver (Box 62)
      - Vasso (Box 62)
      - Design Winners 1960 (Box 62)
      - ICSID Education Seminar (Box 62)
      - Seminar 3 Best Shots (Box 62)
      - Silver Lecture (Box 62)
      - Etras All Seminars (Box 62)
      - Glass Plate Misc. Design (Box 62)
      - 5 Glass Plates Boxes (Box 62)
      - Billboards '89 (Box 62)
      - Pulos 1 Art (Box 62)
      - History (Box 62)
      - Jap. Design —SU Slide (Box 62)
      - Exhibits/ Arch interiors (Box 62)
      - Annual of Display and Commercial Space — Japan '89 (Box 62)
      - Pulos 12 — Japan Slides (Box 62)
      - Pulos 10 — Jap. Design — Pulos Slides (Box 62)
      - Slides of Dept. ID — Central Academy of Arts and Design — Beijing China 1 (Box 62)
      - Slides of Dept. ID — Central Academy of Arts and Design — Beijing China 2 (Box 62)
      - American Design Ethic — Set of Alternative Slides of Illustrations (Box 62)
      - Cornies
        - R (Box 62)
        - AG (Box 62)
        - Sat R. 3-48 (Box 62)
        - Sat L. 49-91 (Box 62)
        - Sat L 2-48 (Box 62)
        - Sat R 48-92 (Box 62)
    - Binders
      - ADA Chapter 8 (Box 63)
      - ADA Chapter 8 (Box 63)
      - ADA Chapter 8 (Box 63)
      - ADA Chapter 6 (Box 63)
      - ADA Chapter 7 (Box 63)
      - ID Annuals 1978-1987 (Box 64)
      - Pulos Book Chapter Notes (Box 65)
      - Preface ADE (Box 65)
      - Chapters 1-9 (Box 65)
      - Epilogue (Box 65)
      - Charts (Box 65)
      - Airplane Structure (Box 65)
      - Audio Tapes of Public Lectures (Box 66)
      - Copies of Interior Magazine 1960's (Box 66)
      - Correspondence 1958-1960 (Box 66)
      - Aircraft Manual (Box 66)
      - Photo Sleeves (Box 66)
      - Card Catalog of Books and Patents (Box 66)
  - Additional material (non-Hollinger boxes)
    - "The Game" (Box 1)
    - Erie Canal and Canastota 1972 sketches (Box 2)